show and the difficulties of getting crypto insurance. Is it getting easier for crypto firms to get
crypto insurance? Well, thank you for having me on the show, Henry. Quick answer, yes.
We have been writing, as you know, insurance for digital assets for over four years now,
and the market has changed hugely in that time. So we now have policies for centralized exchanges,
custodians covering over a billion dollars of digital assets. So that's gone up 100
X since we started doing it, 10 X in the last probably two or three years. So the availability
is coming online. There's no question. What is the biggest difficulty for insurers when they're
looking at the industry? Is it a technical understanding? Is it the risk that they don't know? Is it the
known unknowns? What do you think is the biggest bottleneck you think on that perspective for it
to be easier to get crypto insurance? Yes. So when we say easier, you can take that two ways, right?
Have the technical standards loosened? Have we said, hey, we can cover a bigger range of
technologies here? Not really. Actually, we still expect the highest level of technical standards.
But what you see now is with the institutionalization of the whole space, you see that the centralized
exchanges, the custodians, the asset managers, they're now putting in place way better technical
standards. And so that's allowing us to say, hey, actually, this can be a risk that we can manage.
And we can also manage it at a decent price, because fundamentally, if it's not a decent price,
you can see it's not available. It doesn't make much sense otherwise. But obviously,
I get it. You mentioned centralized exchanges, custodians. What about DeFi? There's obviously
the DeFi ecosystem is growing. We've seen over the last couple of years some new initiatives
actually on DeFi insurance, decentralized insurance. What are you seeing from demand,
from a DeFi world and the possibility for, let's say, centralized insurance to ensure that space as
well? Yeah, it's an area we've been looking at for a long time. And I think what you have to
appreciate, this is a really new sector. So I think it's quite natural that we moved first on the
centralized guys, the exchanges, the custodians. We actually wrote two academic papers on smart
contract risk, DeFi risk. So we're very deep in the understanding of what the risks are in that
area. But as we see every couple of months, a hack of a bridge, a hack of a protocol,
it's still risky. And if it's risky, what you're going to get from the insurance companies is
unfortunately high premiums. So what we're working on there is the security level has got to get
better, and we'll meet them in the middle. But how do you, Robin, when you deal with the insurers
and reinsurers, typically in the insurance sector, it's very conservative. As things move slowly,
people are conservative. How are we able to change or bring crypto and even change the culture in a
way with these organizations to make them embrace crypto? Because I mean, there's so many other
industries that are less risky that they could easily ensure and they've been doing for hundreds
of years. Yeah, well, in the time that I've been doing this, I've seen a massive change in the
thinking of these traditional legacy insurers. To give you an example, when we work in UAE,
we work closely with our partner Dubai Insurance. So when we approached Dubai Insurance several
years ago, it wasn't something really on their radar. But now they see, actually, this is a risk
that we can understand. We can understand what's going on there. And also, it's something that's
quite different from the other risks that they see in their portfolio. So if you look on a global
basis, the reinsurance industry, having a very tough time with climate change risk, anything
physical property. So there's actually a move to say, well, if we can ensure digital property,
that's completely, we say, non-correlated with that physical climate change risk.
So hold the diversification strategy in the way from that perspective,
talking about diversification. Obviously, AI is playing a big role, not only in crypto,
but other verticals as well. Do you believe we can ensure AI or what are the areas of AI that
firms like yours are looking at potentially ensuring? Well, I'll tell you, when we look at AI, we're
following exactly the same playbook as crypto, which is to say, you've got to understand the risk
to a very high level before you even think of putting the insurance policy in place.
So the stage that we're at with AI is still the cybersecurity, the risk management level.
So we've rolled out products, which are penetration tests, guardrails for a large language model,
apps for foundational models. This is us really getting deep into the risk, building up the data
of what the risks are here. Only once we've got a good handle on that, would we move towards
insurance? That could be also bigger than crypto insurance as well. You know, also the journey,
the lifecycle of a customer, when they're looking at buying insurance, including crypto insurance,
let's say it's a bit old school, not to call it outdated, with the forms being set and
the form filled out. The whole process is very manual, many, many intermediaries. Do you believe
actually that crypto couldn't play a role or even smart contracts in making the process more
smoother over the coming years? Yeah, I think absolutely crypto playing a role, getting on crypto
rails and also AI playing a role. So even within our organization, we're very tech forward. Obviously,
our underwriting first pass is done by an AI tool. So we plug in our clients, we work out many of the
risks purely using a large language model solution. So that's cutting the time that it takes for us
to get the client from first meeting to actually offering them a policy. So we're always working
these things and there's a load more to do, but we're pushing it. We have 30 seconds left, Robin.
Quickly, I want to ask, we talk a lot about the future on the show today. The future of insurance.
Let's say we have this interview 10 years from now. How do you think the crypto insurance industry will
look like? Yeah, I think big, big picture is we've got to get the customers closer to who's taking
the risk. So crypto, AI, brilliant chance to disintermediate. Why don't we see if you're holding
some crypto, you want to take a yield, then you can actually be directly putting that into a pool
and that can be covering the crypto risk. Let's bring the customers and the risk much closer together
and blockchains the way to do it, I think.